<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>day-to-day on rizkidoank&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://rizkidoank.com/tags/day-to-day/</link>
    <description>Recent content in day-to-day on rizkidoank&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rizkidoank.com/tags/day-to-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Experience as a Tech Lead</title>
      <link>https://rizkidoank.com/2019/02/23/first-experience-as-a-tech-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizkidoank.com/2019/02/23/first-experience-as-a-tech-lead/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I got offered and trust to be a lead in my team. To be honest, that was my first time I become a lead in my career. First thing that come to my mind was,
 If I become a lead, then I will have N peoples that will be my responsibility, I will be one of the factor of their good and bad
 That was not easy choice, but thanks to my supportive lead and also supportive colleague.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Infra Testing Really Matters?</title>
      <link>https://rizkidoank.com/2019/02/23/does-infra-testing-really-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizkidoank.com/2019/02/23/does-infra-testing-really-matters/</guid>
      <description>Story In previous post, I already share my experience when tried to automate manual process by created script to automatically create configs based on the input in requests. We found that the script are useful enough at that time, and reduced number of incidents caused by misconfiguration (yay!). Unfortunately, we faced with issues when the provisioned infrastructure not work as expected which caused by several things, example: invalid port definition which (again) inputted by human.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Scripting Make My Life Easier</title>
      <link>https://rizkidoank.com/2019/02/23/how-scripting-make-my-life-easier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizkidoank.com/2019/02/23/how-scripting-make-my-life-easier/</guid>
      <description>Story Did you ever worked in repetitive tasks? I was worked as an operational cloud infrastructure engineer. Starting from received several ticket from developers who needs infrastructure, gathering informations for their needs, double check the requests, and everything done manually by myself.. Ouch! Even worse if we missed something from the request, ta-daaa! Incident happened and another requests got delayed.
It does happened to me (and my team) about past one-half years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>