<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>site-reliability-engineer on rizkidoank&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://rizkidoank.com/tags/site-reliability-engineer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in site-reliability-engineer on rizkidoank&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 07:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rizkidoank.com/tags/site-reliability-engineer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Your Ansible Role with Test Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://rizkidoank.com/2018/07/20/test-your-ansible-role-with-test-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 07:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizkidoank.com/2018/07/20/test-your-ansible-role-with-test-kitchen/</guid>
      <description>Its been a while I am using Ansible as a tool for configuration management. There was some conditions where I created a roles with multiple dependencies, or I have to revisit an ancient roles created by someone else in the past. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the roles are well tested, how if its untested or doesn&amp;rsquo;t have tests at all?
In the past, I test ansible role by creating a vagrant box and run ansible playbook in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immutable Infrastructure using Terraform</title>
      <link>https://rizkidoank.com/2018/05/12/immutable-infrastructure-using-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 07:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rizkidoank.com/2018/05/12/immutable-infrastructure-using-terraform/</guid>
      <description>What is Terraform?  Terraform is a tool for building, changing, and versioning infrastructure safely and efficiently.
 OK, that&amp;rsquo;s the first answer when you questioning about &amp;ldquo;what is Terraform&amp;rdquo;. Terraform is a tool built by Hashicorp for infrastructure management. It&amp;rsquo;s based on Go, so you can easily install it by downloading the binary into your machine.
Why Using Terraform? This is a good question, we know that there are some tools besides Terraform for infrastructure management that commonly used out there like Ansible, Chef, or CloudFormation (if you use AWS).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>